Jon-Collin Chinje

Long Island City, NY ❖ (571) 245-2472 ❖ j.chinje@gmail.com

portfolio: http://jon-chinje.com | gh: https://github.com/jcollinc

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack developer with experience in JavaScript, Ruby and React, and a background in project management and research. I have a passion for programming, a desire to engineer scalable software solutions while following proper development standards, and an interest in creating intuitive interfaces for client use.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript; React; Sinatra, Ruby on Rails; SQL; HTML; CSS; Git; GitHub; Quality Control; Intermediate French-speaker

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

ToneBook - GitHub | Live | Demo

An application for musicians which provides a sandbox-style setup for organizing and tracking practice routines

- Built with a **React** front-end, **Ruby on Rails** backend, and deployed via **Heroku**.
- Researched and implemented UI/UX design principles in order to offer an intuitive experience for end users.
- Developed fully custom design using **CSS** custom properties to offer users multiple front-end themes.
- Designed REST API to enable persistence of user routines and exercises.
- Implemented authentication and validation to ensure the security of the app and privacy of user data

Dotify - GitHub (front-end) | GitHub (backend) | Demo

An application for listening to music, watching videos, and maintaining user playlists, built using Sinatra and React

- Created a custom REST API with Ruby/Sinatra to allow for interactable and persistent music playlists.
- Developed robust back-end system to handle complex model associations
- Built a simply themed React front-end, paying attention to design principles and UI conventions

StudyRoom - GitHub | Demo

A message board created for classmates to collaborate on work, with a coffee ordering component; built using React

- Developed a Single Page Application to serve as a message board for cohort-mates
- Managed requests with ison-server and implemented validations to allow only the addition of properly formatted data
- Utilized public APIs to generate sample data for the main component of the app, supplemented this with cohort-specific information.

EXPERIENCE

YRCI Fairfax, VA (remote)

HR Assistant (*new clearances required after previous contract)

Sep 2021 – Dec 2021

- Reviewed applicants for multiple government agencies, offered relevant feedback to applicants as well as hiring managers
- Created listings on USAJobs, held discussions with external hiring managers daily to relay status and address concerns

Documentation / QC Analyst

YRCI

Fairfax, VA Aug. 2019 - April 2021

- Supported Department of State by abstracting legal lease agreements for international properties, using eBrevia software
- Overhauled the previous QC process, making it more streamlined and effective while requiring fewer analysts

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY

Software Engineering

Full Stack Web Development Program, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript

George Mason University Fairfax, VA B.S., Economics

Two semesters of SQL and two further semesters of MATLAB for the purpose of econometric analysis

April 2017

April 2022